Sidney Harwood Collection of Textile Industry Graphics 6890 G
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Sidney Harwood Collection of Textile Industry Graphics
1908
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Sidney Harwood
6890 G
0.11 cubic feet
0.1 linear ft.
Photomechanical prints, relief halftones (prints), relief photomechanical processes.
Engineering drawings and blueprints for textile machinery.
10066405
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 16, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, December 06, 2017
Scope and Contents
Engineering drawings from James Hunter Machine Company for wool washers (text in Spanish). Engineering drawings from Davis & Furber Machine Company for finisher cards, breaker cards, burr machines, and pickers. Also includes blueprints for carding machines and oilers designed by Fred Spivey.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6890 P: Sidney Harwood Collection of Textile Industry Photographs
Carding-machines; Cotton-waste; Pickers (Weaving); Textile machinery; Wool -- Washing; Heckmondwike, West Yorkshire, England; North Adams (Mass.); North Andover (Mass.); Spivey, Fred; Davis & Furber Machine Co.; James Hunter Machine Company; Low Mills
10066405
- Engineering drawings and blueprints (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Modelo D Rastrillos Paralelos, Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Tanque de 48 plgs. por 24 pies [1.22 por 7.30 m]. James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass., E.U.A. [Wool washer?]. Halftone, ca. 1910. The James Hunter Machine Co. did business in numerous South American countries and Cuba; this print was clearly meant for the Spanish-speaking market. Image of machinery; company logo in upper left-hand corner. 37.5 x 25.5 cm.
  - Item 2: Lavadora de Lana Modelo D con Rastrillos Independientes [Model D Wool Washer with Independent Rake], Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Tanque de 48 plgs. por 16 pies [feet] [1.22 por 4.88 m.]. James Hunter Machine Co., North Adams, Mass., E.U.A. Halftone, ca. 1910. The James Hunter Machine Co. did business in numerous South American countries and Cuba; this print was clearly meant for the Spanish-speaking market. Image shows wool washer; company logo is in the upper left-hand corner of the print. 38 x 25 cm.
  - Item 3: Finisher Card, 60 Inch Diameter, with Double Apron Rubb and Winding Frame., 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of finisher wool card [with Apperly-type feed]. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1908 (see p. 21). 23 x 15.5 cm.
  - Item 4: Breaker Card, 48 Inch Diameter, with Single Burr Machine., 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of [first] breaker wool card [with Bramwell feed]. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1908 (see p. 20). 23 x 15 cm.
  - Item 5: 59 In. Diam. Breaker with No. 17 Garnet Breast, 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of breaker with garnet breast; eight 7 in. workers on card proper and three on the breast. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1908 (see p. 16). 23 x 15 cm. Copy A.
  - Item 6: 60 In. Diam. Breaker with No. 17 Garnet Breast, 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of breaker with garnet breast; eight 7 in. workers on card proper and three on the breast. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1908 (see p. 16). Copy B. 23 x 15 cm.
  - Item 7: 60 In. Diam. Breaker with No. 17 Garnet Breast, 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of breaker with garnet breast; eight 7 in. workers on card proper and three on the breast. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1908 (see p. 16). Copy C. 23 x 15 cm.
  - Item 8: Burr Machines, 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical print. Photomechanical print of three views of burr machines: single burr machine; single burr machine with lumper; and double burr machine. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1908 (see p. 18). 15.5 x 23 cm.
  - Item 9: All Iron Construction Fearnaught Picker, 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of Fearnaught picker. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1909 (see p. 9). 23 x 15.5 cm. Copy A.
  - Item 10: All Iron Construction Fearnaught Picker, 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of Fearnaught picker. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1909 (see p. 9). Copy B. 23 x 15.5 cm.
  - Item 11: Cotton Waste Type Breaker Card, 1908; Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Davis & Furber Machine Company, North Andover, Mass. A. Mugford, Boston [engraver?]. Photomechanical halftone print. Photomechanical halftone print of cotton waste type breaker card. Illustration from Davis & Furber trade catalogue of 1908 (see p. 34). 23 x 15.5 cm.
  - Item 12: End Elevation of Spivey's Patent Duplex Oiling Machine, Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Fred Spivey, Low Mills, Heckmondwike, West Yorkshire, England. Bluepint. 1 1/2 " = 1 '. 29.5 x 26.5 cm.
  - Item 13: Spivey's Patent Oiling Motion for Gill Box, Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Fred Spivey, Low Mills, Heckmondwike, West Yorkshire, England. Bluepint. 91 x 45 cm.
  - Item 14: Spivey's Patent Oiling Machine, Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Fred Spivey, Low Mills, Heckmondwike, West Yorkshire, England. Bluepint. Print no.40. For oiling wool, shoddy, hair, rags, etc. 50 x 31 cm.
  - Item 15: Carding by Rollers, Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Fred Spivey, Low Mills, Heckmondwike, West Yorkshire, England. Bluepint. Broad band feed for Garnett card. Side elevation of carding machine. 37.5 x 25 cm.
  - Item 16: Double Worsted Card, Graphics (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Built by Davis & Furber Machine Co., North Andover, Mass. With Improved Bramwell Feed Built by Geo. S. Harwood & Sons. Photolithograph, n.d. Image of carding machine. Probably built for the Wood Mill, Lawrence, Mass., according to the donor. 43 x 36 cm.